<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recep&#39;s Technical Blog</title>
    <link>https://erolrecep.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Recep&#39;s Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:18:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://erolrecep.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GNU Parallel for Your Terminal Tasks</title>
      <link>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/gnuparallel_for_your_terminal_tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 21:18:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/gnuparallel_for_your_terminal_tasks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world, efficiency is key, especially when working with multiple files and processes. Enter &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gnu.org/software/parallel/&#34;&gt;GNU Parallel&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful command-line tool that can help you streamline your terminal tasks by running them in parallel. In this blog post, we’ll explore what GNU Parallel is, how to install and use it, and some practical use cases that demonstrate its capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-gnu-parallel&#34;&gt;What is GNU Parallel?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU Parallel is a command-line utility designed to execute jobs in parallel, leveraging your system&amp;rsquo;s resources more effectively. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re converting files, processing data, or running scripts, if you can do it in the terminal, you can probably use GNU Parallel to speed it up. This tool is perfect for anyone who relies on the terminal for their daily tasks and wants to optimize their workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Checklist</title>
      <link>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/workshop_checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 05:47:10 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/workshop_checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;before&#34;&gt;Before&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Technical content preparation:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;List all the topics you want to teach and write a few paragraphs for each of them (this way, you can easily use the content in your speech)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare GitHub repository to put all the workshop content there, including:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Presentation&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always prepare extra slides, hands-on exercises, or technical content to deliver during the workshop in case the audience is more experienced or knowledgeable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explanations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hands-on exercises&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use case scenarios&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Future works&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plan the workshop in advance:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Duration of the workshop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Date and time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The flow of the workshop&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare a script for the workshop (what you will talk about and in what order)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Logistics (arrange room/office, other required things, etc)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Determine the pre-requisites for the workshop and add them to the announcement:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bring your own laptop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure the browser is working&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You should have an account for the HPC system&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Announcement (Determine a platform and make the announcement. You can also distribute it through the email list of your institute.)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare a survey and asked them to fill right after the workshop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;during&#34;&gt;During&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Welcome users, and make sure they are seated and ready to start the workshop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Talk to the users and learn more about them while introducing yourself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make things interactive. You ask them and allow them to ask you. Learn more about their technical background and determine the pace of the workshop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Based on the progress, determine the level of knowledge to deliver.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always measure the interest of audience and change gears as necessary to spark their interest.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Never judge their level of knowledge! &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; They are here to learn from you. Be as helpful as possible!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In each workshop, ask them to take notes and give them a few minutes intervally so they can keep up. Otherwise, they&amp;rsquo;re going to forget!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always take notes and catch what worked/didn&amp;rsquo;t work, or what you missed and fix this for the next workshops!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Be conscious of any kind of input from the audience&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Give the link of the resources (i.e. GitHub repository) and make sure your audience can access all the resources.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;after&#34;&gt;After&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At the end of the workshop, deliver the survey information (either qrcode, link, or email them) for feedback. &lt;em&gt;evaluation survey&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Each workshop is a good time for self-reflection and opportunity for your growth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consider the feedback results and implement them to the workshop appropriately.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Organizing a Workshop</title>
      <link>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/notes_for_organizing_workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 05:26:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erolrecep.github.io/posts/notes_for_organizing_workshops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This post shares insights on organizing a technical workshop on a university campus. As an HPC admin and AI facilitator, I’ve organized several workshops and technical training sessions for HPC users. Here’s a roadmap of what to do &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;during&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; a workshop, along with tips and tricks to make life easier for both you and the attendees. These are my personal views.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From ML Engineer to HPC Admin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;After working as a machine learning engineer in various companies over a decade, I decided to switch my career to high-performance computing (HPC) and supercomputing centers. Upon completing my PhD, I reflected on my background and realized that the role of an HPC admin and AI facilitator fit perfectly with my skill set. I had also spent years in academia, teaching multiple courses, preparing quizzes and assignments, and mentoring over 100 graduate students in programming, problem-solving, data science, machine learning, and AI. These experiences motivated me to pursue this path.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://erolrecep.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://erolrecep.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
